<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-27T18:59:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Jellyfish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/jellyfish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jellyfish" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/jellyfish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/jellyfish.html">&lt;p&gt;Jellyfish are some of the strangest organisms on planet Earth. They remind me more of biological programs, written in the language of chemistry and executed on earth.io. They sort of just float around the ocean, hardly any agency of their own. Everything about them just seems automatic. They have no brain at all. What is their purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it intrinsic to their being or defined by their relationships and interactions with the environment? What does it even mean to have a purpose? A suppose to have a purpose implies the existence of an agent with a limited perspective from which a purpose can be projected. For a shrimp (do jellyfish eat shrimp?) the purpose of the jellyfish may be to kill shrimp. Depending on which kind of human you ask, a jellyfish might have several purposes. We might say they fulfill some ecological niche, or that they inspire beauty. But intrinsically, without projecting human agents, they are purposeless Jellyfish simply exist, an automated, self-replicating machine built out of carbon. Ephemeral, untethered, dulling simply and yet fantastically complex. Jellyfish remind us that we too are ultimately purposeless; incredibly complex, self-replicating biological machines miraculously capable of contemplating their own existence. They remind us that existence at all is a gift, one worth cherishing while we can.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah</name></author><summary type="html">Jellyfish are some of the strangest organisms on planet Earth. They remind me more of biological programs, written in the language of chemistry and executed on earth.io. They sort of just float around the ocean, hardly any agency of their own. Everything about them just seems automatic. They have no brain at all. What is their purpose?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Endeavor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/endeavor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Endeavor" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/endeavor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/27/endeavor.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting a new project is always daunting. The weight of your own expectations makes it difficult for the project to ever take off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this website basically to prove to myself that I can; I don’t need a the rigorous structure of a university course or homework in order to make me do something productive and worthwhile. I want to show myself and the world that I am capable, that I can build something from the ground-up; that I can figure things out, learn from mistakes, and create something beautiful. Plus if I ever want to do freelance data science or programming work, I think it would be a good idea to have my own portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Noah</name></author><summary type="html">Starting a new project is always daunting. The weight of your own expectations makes it difficult for the project to ever take off.</summary></entry></feed>